# **Dmitrii** Lisin

# Software Programmer, Embedded Programmer

190000, Saint Petersburg, Saint Petersburg RU

@mrlisdim (https://t.me/mrlisdim)

in dmitrii-lisin (https://www.linkedin.com/in/dmitrii-lisin/)



Since childhood, I've been in love with programming. When I began my career as an intern at an electronics design firm, I discovered that I enjoyed creating something that worked in real life rather than just inside my computer. I have finished a lot of embedded projects from different spheres and dealt with numerous instruments, protocols, and peripherals. It has always been my intention to write only high-quality, human-readable code. Had prior team leadership experience, but preferred to work as an equal member of the team. In my free time, I also prefer to extend my knowledge of programming languages, techniques, and trends by working with hobby projects.

#### **SKILLS**

Embedded Development Master	Python Development Advanced	CI/CD Intermediate
C/C++   Zephyr   FreeRTOS   STM32   Nordic   Real-time protocols   Industrial protocols   Stack only programming	FastAPI   Pydantic   ORM   WAMP protocol   Async   Threading	Docker   Docker Compose   Github Actions   Gitlab Pipelines
Web Development Intermediate	Rust Beginner	Common
		VSC   Gitlab   Github   Reviewing
HTML   CSS   JavaScript   Typescript	Tauri	Linux   Reading schematics
React   Parcel   Rollup		Datasheet exploring

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2020 - Current

Team leader at LLC "Third Pin"

Developed a flexible testing system for embedded electronics based on distributed micro-services connected by PubSub/RPC Web-protocol.

- Robster: flexible testing system for electronic devices (Python, WAMP, Microservice, Docker, PostgreSQL)
- Gate valve controller (ARM, STM32, Zephyr, Modbus)
- GPS tracker for a professional training (ARM, Nordic, GPS, UBlox, Ant)

2013 - 2020

## Embedded Software Developer at LLC "Third Pin"

Have been finished more than 20 commercial projects in embedded area including IoT, safety systems, shipbuilding.

- Pastilda: hardware password manager (STM32, ARM, Crypto Peripheral, SDIO, FatFS, FreeRTOS)
- Ship ruder control system (ARM, STM32, USB HID, FreeRTOS)
- Fire alarm system (ARM, STM32)
- MTUTA: Telemetry of vending machines (ARM, FreeRTOS, USB, SD, SIMCom, GSM, Ethernet, FTP)

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Pastilda**

2016 - 2017

team/pastilda) https://bitbucket.org/thirdpin\_team/pastilda (https://bitbucket.org/thirdpin\_team/pastilda)

Skills acquired: C++ | Embedded | Open-source

Open-source hardware designed to manage our credentials in handy and secure way.

#### Just Run My Debugger!

2021 - Current

Skills acquired: Rust | Rescript | Tauri | React

Pet project, simple GUI for OpenOCD debugger.

### **EDUCATION**

 $\textbf{Master Intelligent Technologies in Robotics} \text{ at } \mathsf{ITMO} \text{ University}$ 

2016 - 2018

Bachelor Intelligent Technologies in Robotics at ITMO University

2012 - 2016

# **LANGUAGES**

**English** Russian
Fluent Native Speaker

**INTERESTS** 

Games Books Traveling

**Hobby programming**